Guide to the A'Becket family diaries and prompt books, 1840-1890
The New York Public Library. Billy Rose Theatre Division.
A'Becket family diaries and prompt books
1840-1890
*T-Mss 1991-002
21285
A'Becket family
The New York Public Library. Billy Rose Theatre Division. New York Public Library for the Performing Arts, Dorothy and Lewis B. Cullman Center 40 Lincoln Center Plaza, New York, NY 10023-7498
1.5 lin. ft. (5 boxes)
The A'Becket Family Diaries and Prompt Books include handwritten memoirs and daily notations regarding the life and career of Thomas A'Becket, Sr. from 1844 to 1890. The diaries show the extent of A'Becket's theatrical activities. The diaries of his son, Thomas A'Becket, Jr. are primarily music related. These diaries span the years 1862 to 1880. The scripts and prompt books are sometimes annotated and sometimes unmarked and belonged to Thomas A'Becket, Sr. They span his career and some give information on the theater and year of the production. The collection appears to be a useful research source for detailing the life of a stock actor, writer and musician of the 19th century. A'Becket includes information on his work schedule and his travel schedule in the circuit theaters. Information as well, regarding his family, friends and acquaintances can be found in the diaries.
Thomas A'Becket, Sr. was an actor, musician and writer in the Philadelphia theatre from 1840 to 1889. He acted for both the Arch Street Theatre Company and the Walnut Street Theatre Company though the greatest portion of his time was spent at the Walnut. He acted there 1841-1842;1845- 1847; 1849-1855. After this time he seemed to travel, taking acting jobs in Chicago, St. Louis and other Midwestern cities. A'Becket was known as a major player in the Walnut Street Theatre and played many roles among them Polonius in HAMLET. A'Becket was born on March 17, 1808 and died in Philadelphia on January 6, 1890.
Thomas A'Becket, Jr. was a musician who worked in the Philadelphia area performing in concert ensembles. He also gave music lessons on a daily basis. He was born June 19, 1843, the oldest child of Thomas A'Becket, Sr.
The A'Becket Family Diaries and Prompt Books were purchased by the Billy Rose Theatre Division in 1987 from The Center for Musical Antiquities.
The A'Becket Family Diaries and Prompt Books include handwritten memoirs and daily notations of his life and career from 1844 to 1890. The diaries show the extent of A'Becket's theatrical and musical career giving brief but itemized accounts of his daily activities. The diaries of his son, Thomas A'Becket, Jr. are not truly theatre related, as his career was primarily a musician. These diaries span the years 1862 to 1880. The scripts and prompt books are sometimes annotated and sometimes unmarked and belonged to Thomas A'Becket, Sr. They span his career, and some give information on the theater and year of the production. The collection appears to be a useful research source for detailing the life of a stock actor, writer and musician of the 19th century. Becket includes information of his work schedule and his travel schedule in the circuit theaters. Information as well, regarding his friends and acquaintances can be found in the diaries.
The A'Becket Family Diaries and Prompt Books are arranged in three series. They are:
I. Thomas A'Becket, Sr. Diaries, 1844-1890
II. Thomas A'Becket, Jr. Diaries, 1862-1880
III. Scripts and Prompt Books
Purchase, Center for Musical Antiquities, 1987
Collection is open to the public. Library policy on photography and photocopying will apply. Advance notice may be required.
Photocopying prohibited.
A'Becket family; Allingham, John Till, fl. 1799-1810; Almar, George; Barnett, C. Z. (Charles Zachary); Beazley, Samuel, 1786-1851; Becket, Thomas à, 1808-1890; Becket, Thomas à, 1843-1918; Boucicault, Dion, 1820-1890; Brown, John, 1715-1766; Buckstone, John Baldwin, 1802-1879; Cobb, James, 1756-1818; Colman, George, 1762-1836; Cooper, Frederick Fox, 1806-1879; Cowley, Mrs. (Hannah), 1743-1809; Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811; Kotzebue, August von, 1761-1819; Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1803-1873; Macfarren, George, 1788-1843; O'Keeffe, John, 1747-1833; Oulton, Walley Chamberlain, 1770?-1820?; Penley, S. (Samson); Tobin, John, 1770-1804; Walnut Street Theatre (Philadelphia, Pa.); Theater -- United States -- 19th century; Stranger; Diaries; Actors
- Series I: Thomas A'Becket, Sr. Diaries, 1844-1890; 561478; .8 lin. ft. (2 boxes)
  The diaries of Thomas A'Becket, Sr., span the years 1844 to 1890 and include information on his theatrical career, during the years he worked in Philadelphia as well as the time he spent in out-of-town productions. There is also much information on his personal and family life and records on a daily basis the life of a 19th century acting family.
  Chronological.
  - Diary, 1844; 561479 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1845; 561480 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1846; 561481 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1847; 561482 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1848; 561483 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1849; 561484 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1850; 561485 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1851; 561486 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1852; 561487 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1853; 561488 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 1855; 561489 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Diary, 1856; 561490 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Diary, 1857; 561491 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Diary, 1861; 561492 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Diary, 1863; 561493 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Diary, 1864; 561494 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Diary, 1865; 561495 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Diary, 1867; 561496 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Diary, 1871; 561497 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Diary, 1872; 561498 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Diary, 1873; 561499 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Diary, 1874; 561500 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Diary, 1875; 561501 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1876; 561502 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1877; 561503 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1878; 561504 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1879; 561505 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1880; 561506 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1881; 561507 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1882; 561508 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1883; 561509 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1884; 561510 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 1885; 561511 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Diary, 1886; 561512 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Diary, 1887; 561513 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Diary, 1888; 561514 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Diary, 1889; 561515 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Diary, 1890; 561516 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Diary (odd unidentified fragments), 561517 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series II: Thomas A'Becket, Jr. Diaries, 1862-1889; 561518; .6 lin. ft. (2 boxes)
  The diaries include information on his daily activities and span the years 1862-1885. Included as well are two engagement books which have appointment information. There is also a picture of Thomas A'Becket, Jr. in this series.
  - Diary, 1862; 561519 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1864; 561520 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1866; 561521 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1867; 561522 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1868; 561523 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1869; 561524 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1874; 561525 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1875; 561526 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1876; 561527 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1877; 561528 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 1878; 561529 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Diary, 1879; 561530 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Diary, 1880; 561531 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Diary, 1881; 561532 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1882; 561533 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1883; 561534 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1884; 561535 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1885; 561536 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Engagement Book, 1867-1879; 561537 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Engagement Book, 1872-1880; 561538 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photograph of Thomas A'Becket, Jr., 1889; 561539 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series III: Scripts and Prompt Books, 561540; .4 lin ft. (1 box)
  This series contains published scripts, many annotated for productions which A'Becket, Sr. was involved in. All the plays are from the late 18th and 19th century.
  Alphabetical
  - The Agreeable Surprise by Mr. O'Keefe [Belfast: ], 1785; 561541 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Barbarossa by Dr. Brown [New York: ], 1809; 561542 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Belle's Stratagem by Mrs. Cowley [Boston: ], 1810; 561543 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Blue Devils by George Colman, the younger [Philadelphia: ], 1811; 561544 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bold Stroke for a Husband by Mrs. Cowley [New York: ], 1831; 561545 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Cedar Chest by George Almar [London: n.d.], 561546 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Clerk of Clerkenwell by George Almar[London: n.d.], 561547 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Damon and Pythias by John Baldwin Buckstone [London: n.d.], 561548 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fire and Water by S. Beazley [New York: ] and The Sleeping Draught by S. Penley [Baltimore: ], 1821; 1818; 561549 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fortune's Frolic by John Till Allingham [New York: ], 1824; 561550 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Guy Faux by George Marfarren [n.d.], 561551 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Honey Moon by John Tobin [London: n.d.], 561552 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Ion by Fox Cooper [London: n.d.], 561553 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Irish Lion by John Baldwin Buckstone [Philadelphia: n.d.], 561554 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Iron Chest by George Colman, the younger [London: n.d.], 561555 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Jealous On All Sides by S. Beazley, Jun. [Philadelphia: ], 1818; 561556 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - My Landlady's Gown by W. C. Oulton [Baltimore: ], 1817; 561557 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - London Assurance by Dion Boucicault [Baltimore: ], 1817; 561558 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Love Laughs at Locksmiths by George Colman, the younger [London: n.d.], 561559 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Money by Edward Bulwer Lytton [New York: n.d.], 561560 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Paul and Virginia by James Cobb [London: n.d.], 561561 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pedlar's Acre by George Almar [London: n.d.], 561562 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Popping the Question by John Baldwin Buckstone [London: n.d.], 561563 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - The Poor Gentleman by George Colman, the younger [n.d.], 561564 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - The Review; or The Wags of Windsor by George Colman, the younger [New York: ], 1817; 561565 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - The Rise of the Rothschildes by C. Z. Barnett [London: n.d.], 561566 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - The Siege of Belgrade by James Cobb [New York: ], 1823; 561567 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - The Stranger by Benjamin Thompson [New York: n.d.], 561568 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Uncle John by John Baldwin Buckstone [Philadelphia: n.d.], 561569 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - The Weathercock by John Till Allingham [Philadelphia: ], 1826; 561570 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - The Wheel of Fortune by Richard Cumberland [London: n.d.], 561571 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - X,Y,Z; or, The American Manager by George Colman, Esq. [New York :], 1828; 561572 (Box 5, Folder 32)